# MOSHOOD RAFIU

+2348144259341 rafiumoshoodolakunle@gmail.com

# **SUMMARY**

An innovative software engineer with a 5-year Computer Engineering degree and 2 years of experience. Wellversed in technology and writing code to develop software that is reliable and user-friendly. A creative tech enthusiast with a talent for critical reasoning and problem-solving, and a passion to contribute to how the internet is progressing and how technology is evolving.

## **EMPLOYMENT**

### **Full Stack Developer, Remote Cultuzz Digital Media GmbH, Germany**

July 2021 - Present

- Optimized the speed of booking channels mapper by 50% by grouping multiple relevant fetch requests into a single request and optimizing database query.
- · Integrate new and existing products with multiple property management systems.
- Implement new user interface design using modern web technologies.
- · Leveraged knowledge in third-party API integration, Docker, Git, JavaScript, PHP, Vue JS, Laravel and MySQL databases.

# **Full Stack Developer, Contract**

# **BigCommand LLC, USA**

Nov 2021 - July 2022

- Implemented a new user interface for the video hosting channel and optimized its load time by 70% by implementing lazy loading and rewriting of the relevant database queries.
- · Refactored the watch history feature of videos for improved analytics and reduced bandwidth utilization on the server by 35%.
- Developed a viral campaign feature which increased the application users by 15% in the following month.
- Leveraged knowledge in Git, JavaScript, PHP, Vue JS, Laravel and MySQL databases.

# **Backend Developer, Intern**

# Atata57, Nigeria.

July 2020 - Feb 2021

- Developed a cart system for an e-commerce application to handle the cart of both authenticated and unauthenticated users.
- Developed REST API endpoints and wrote detailed documentation using Swagger.
- · Leveraged knowledge in REST API development, PHP, Laravel, MySQL database and Swagger.

# **EDUCATION**

# Lagos, Nigeria

# **Lagos State University**

Dec 2016 – July 2022

- Major: Electronic and Computer Engineering (CGPA: 4.76 of 5.0)
- Relevant Coursework: Introduction to Programming in Python, Data Structures & Algorithms, Operating Systems, Computer Network, Database System Design and Management, Object Oriented Programming.

## **SOFTWARE PROJECTS**

Portfolio Website: https://moshoodrafiu.netlify.app (for additional information and projects)

# **COVID-19 Self-Testing Software**

- Developed a web application using JavaScript and PHP that allows users to take a COVID-19 self-test, and then suggests the nearest COVID-19 centres based on location if the risk level is high.
- <u>Utilized</u>: JavaScript, PHP, Python, Laravel, Vue JS, MySQL, HTML/CSS, Numpy, Scikit Learn.

# **Hotel Management Software**

- Developed a web-based and mobile-friendly application to manage the day-to-day activities in hotels and generate extensive reports based on demand.
- Utilized: JavaScript, PHP, Laravel, Vue JS, MySQL, HTML/CSS.

Software: (proficient) JavaScript, PHP, Git, HTMS/CSS, MySQL (familiar) Python, Matlab, AWS.